MARTIN ZERBIB

TECHNOLOGY EVANGELIST

martinzerbib@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/martinzerbib 813-294-4083

Nationality: French

Passionate technology advocate with both consumer and enterprise experience in data-driven technologies.

Overview	Technology Driven	Web Development	Customer Facing
	Able to learn and adapt quickly to new languages and technologies and apply them effectively to work responsibilities.	Development of web applications for demos, proof of concepts and production, using a wide variety of languages and frameworks.	Experience in delivering workshops and presentations both to large audiences as well as to C-Level executives.
Technical	Javascript/Jquery	Ruby	Linux
Skills	Python	Enterprise Search	MySQL/PostgreSQL
	Java	Presentations/Speaking	Swift/PHP/Apex/C/C++/.NET

Experience

HP Software Big Data- San Francisco

October 2013 - Present

Developer Evangelist

Working on the Haven Platform, a combination of Cloud and On Premise solution for unstructured data analytics and search (IDOL), and big data analytics (Vertica). IDOLOnDemand.com, Vertica OnDemand

Developed Evangelist strategy; initiated developer events, collaborating with local organizers; built a developer community; responsible for technical writing of API references; documentation and presentations; developed applications, client libraries, demos and code examples; public speaking, media engagement, event coordination.

Sample work: Video: Face Recognition Nerf gun

Notable events attended: Mobile World Congress '15 (Talk), Developer Week '15 (Talk), API World '14 (Talk), Topcoder Open '14 (Judge)

HP Autonomy - London

Senior Pre-Sales Technical Consultant

July 2011 - October 2013

Led pre-sales and post-sales engagements in Europe in the matters of enterprise search, social media analytics and web content management.

Provided subject matter expertise, project guidance, and consulting leadership to diverse clientele on HP Autonomy products along with other adjacent technologies.

Multiple overlaps with professional services and delivery due to strong technical skills, in charge of projects from sales opportunity to delivery.

Notable projects:

- User targeted recommendation engine for a top 2000 alexa rank News site.
- Distributed social media analytics solution ingesting and analysing multi million tweets, news articles and intranet docs each
- Multiple enterprise search solutions: Sizing, Architecture, Design, Implementation, Data Ingestion, Optimization

UBS Investment Bank- London IT Intern

London, June 2009 - September 2009

Java intern, worked on banking solutions and products, participated in planning, design, implementation and decision making.

Imperial College London Undergraduate teaching assistant

2008 - 2010

Taught tutorial sessions and marked Mathematics-based coursework.

Holland Park School **Mathematics Teaching Assistant**

2008

Assisted with, taught and created lesson plans for KS3 and KS4 Mathematics students.

Education

Imperial College London

MSci Joint Mathematics and Computer Science, 2.1

2006 - 2010

Languages

- Native French
- Fluent English
- Elementary German